Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations PE.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- W, 1885-2012; 13.25 Linear Feet in 11 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 2 shared manuscript boxes, and 1 oversize shared box
  - Wooden Shoe Books and Records (Philadelphia, PA), 1979- (Box 108)
    Wooden Shoe Books and Records was a collectively run anarchist bookshop.
  - Woodstock Anarchist Party (Stockton, CA), 1978 (Box 108)
  - Woody Guthrie Foundation, 2008- (Box 108)
  - Woolwich Invalid Children's Aid Committee, 1904 (Box 108)
  - Worcester Action Research on the Military-Industrial Complex (WARMIC), 1973 (Box 108)
  - Work in America Institute, 1980 (Box 130, Folder 17)
  - Work People's College (Duluth, MN), 1926- (Box 108)
  - Worker, the, 1944-, undated (Box 108)
  - Worker-Client Alliance, undated (Box 108)
  - Worker-Student Organizing Committee (New York, NY), 1977- (Box 108)
  - Worker/Welfare Research and Advocacy Project, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Action, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Action Movement, 1973- (Box 108)
  - Workers Against Work for Social Warfare, undated (Box 108, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 24)
  - Workers Age Publishers, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Aim Cooperative Association (Jersey Homesteads, NJ), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Alliance of America, 1936- (Box 108)
  - Workers Alliance of Greater New York, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Alliance of New Jersey, 1937 (Box 108)
  - Workers Alliance of Tulsa, circa 1936 (Box 108)
  - Workers Alliance: Federal Arts Council (New York, NY), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Book Shop (New York, NY), 1956- (Box 108)
  - Workers Book Shop (Philadelphia, PA), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Bookshop (London, U.K.), 1934- (Box 108)
  - Workers Challenge (New York, NY), 1921 (Box 108)
  - Workers Committee Against Wage Controls (Hayward, CA), 1973- (Box 108)
  - Workers Committee to Throw the Bum Out (President Richard M. Nixon), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Communist League (U.S.), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers (Communist) Party of America, 1925 (Box 108)
  - Workers (Communist) Party of America, 1925-1928 (Box 108)
  - Workers (Communist) Party of America, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Conference on Labor Legislation, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers Congress (Marxist-Leninist), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Cooperative Colony (New York, NY): Allerton Coops, 1944- (Box 108)
  - Workers Dance League, 1933 (Box 108)
  - Workers Defense Committee, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense Conference (Haverhill, MA), undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1936-1938, 1969 (Box 108, Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1940 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1941 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1942-1947 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1948-1956 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1957 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1958-1962 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1963-1969 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1970-1979 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1982-1992 (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League, 1993- (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League I, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense League II, undated (Box 108)
  - Workers' Defense Union (New York, NY), 1918- (Box 108)
    Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material (PE 040) also contains a Workers' Defense Union file.
  - Workers' Democracy (St. Louis, MO), 1983- (Box 108)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1922-1929 (Box 108)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1934-1938 (Box 108)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America I, 1941-1949 (Box 109)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America II, 1941-1949 (Box 109)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers' Educational Association (Great Britain), 1950- (Box 109)
  - Workers' Educational Association of Norway, 1969- (Box 109)
  - Workers' Educational Association of Ontario, 1923- (Box 109)
  - Workers Ex-Servicemen's League (New York, NY), 1932 (Box 109)
  - Workers Fight Tendency, 1968 (Box 130, Folder 19)
  - Workers for a Democratic Society (San Diego, CA), undated (Box 109)
  - Workers' Health Bureau I, 1924- (Box 109)
  - Workers' Health Bureau II, 1924- (Box 109)
  - Workers' International League Fourth International, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers' International Relief, 1929 (Box 109)
  - Workers League I, 1967- (Box 109)
  - Workers League II, 1967- (Box 109)
  - Workers League III, 1967- (Box 109)
  - Workers League IV, 1967- (Box 109)
  - Workers League of Greater New York, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Liberation Army, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers' Museum (Copenhagen, Denmark), undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Music League, 1932 (Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 24)
  - Workers' Olympiad (Cleveland, OH), 1936 (Box 109)
  - Workers Party (England), undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Party (Ireland), 1987- (Box 109)
  - Workers' Party: Jewish Section, 1924 (Box 109)
  - Workers Party: New York Local, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Party (San Francisco, CA), 1979- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party for Proletarian Socialism (San Francisco, CA), 1977- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of America, 1921-1925 (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of America, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of Canada, 1936 (Box 109)
  - Worker's Party of Jamaica, 1984 (Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 25)
  - Workers Party of Maryland, 1967- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of the United States I, 1935-1949 (Box 109, Box 130, Folder 20)
  - Workers Party of the United States II, 1935- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of the United States III, 1935- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of the United States IV, 1935- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party of the United States V, 1935- (Box 109)
  - Workers Party: Songs and Skits, undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Policy Project, 1983- (Box 109)
  - Workers Power (New York, NY), undated (Box 109)
  - Workers Press (Chicago, IL), 1975- (Box 109)
  - Workers' Press (China), 1952, 1955 (Box 109)
  - Workers Prison Relief Committee of Paterson, N.J., 1923- (Box 109)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1925-1935 (Box 110, Box 127, Folder 42)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1931-1933 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1934 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1935-1936 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1937 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) I, 1938 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) II, 1938 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1939 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) I, 1940 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) II, 1940 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) III, 1940 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY), 1941 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) I, 1942 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) II, 1942 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) I, 1943 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) II, 1943 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) I, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY) II, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): American Labor Movement, Course Packets on, 1934 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Communist International, Soviet Communist Party, Course Packets on, 1936 (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Communist Party USA, Course Packets on, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): English, Course Packets on Learning I, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): English, Course Packets on Learning II, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Marxism-Leninism, Course Packets on I, undated (Box 110)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Marxism-Leninism, Course Packets on II, undated (Box 111)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Negro History, Course Packets on, 1930- (Box 111)
  - Workers School (New York, NY): Victoria Review (script), undated (Box 111)
  - Workers School of Boston, 1935 (Box 111)
  - Workers' Socialist Federation, 1919 (Box 111)
  - Workers' Socialist Party (Boston, MA), 1936- (Box 111)
  - Workers Socialist Party of the United States, 1935- (Box 111)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance I, 1989- (Box 111)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance II, 1989-, undated (Box 111)
  - Workers Solidarity Club (Youngstown, OH), undated (Box 111)
  - Workers' Sports League of America, 1935- (Box 111)
  - Workers' Theatre (New York, NY), 1931- (Box 111)
  - Workers Tribune, undated (Box 111)
  - Workers University of Mexico (Universidad Obrera de Mexico), 1948 (Box 111)
  - Workers Vanguard Publishing Association (Toronto, Canada), 1962- (Box 111)
  - Workers World Left Opposition (Milwaukee, WI), undated (Box 111)
  - Workers Viewpoint (New York, NY), undated (Box 111)
  - Workers World Party (New York, NY) I, 1962, undated (Box 111, Box 130, Folder 21)
  - Workers World Party (New York, NY) II, 1962-, undated (Box 111)
  - Workforce Development Institute, 2010 (Box 111)
  - Working Class Movement Library, 1979- (Box 111)
  - Working Families Party (New York, NY), 1998- (Box 111)
  - Working Men's Association, undated (Box 111)
  - Working Men's Club and Institute Union, 1899 (Box 111)
  - Working People's Alliance (Guyana), 1981- (Box 111)
  - Working People's News (Silver Springs, MD), undated (Box 111)
  - Working Peoples Party of England, undated (Box 111)
  - Working Theatre (New York, NY), 1995- (Box 111)
  - Working Women's Conference, undated (Box 130, Folder 22)
  - Working Women for Jobs, Peace and Freedom, 1984 (Box 111)
  - Working Women, National Association of Office Workers I, 1979- (Box 111)
  - Working Women, National Association of Office Workers II, 1979- (Box 111)
  - Working Women's Institute (New York, NY), 1979- (Box 111)
  - Working Women's Society (New York, NY), 1893 (Box 111)
  - Workingmen's Co-operative Publishing Association/ New York Call, 1911- (Box 111)
  - Workingmen's Furniture Fire Insurance, 1907 (Box 111)
  - Workingwoman's Association, undated (Box 111)
  - Workman's Protective Association (Christopher, IL), undated (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Benefit Fund, 1899 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY), 1900-1959 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY), 1960-1969 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY), 1970-1979 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY), 1980-1989 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY), 1990- (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY) I, undated (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle (New York, NY) II, undated (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle: Amalgamated I.L. Peretz School 3 (New York, NY), 1958 (Box 111)
  - Workmen's Circle: Branch 1054 (Northern California), 1998 (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle Chorus (New York, NY), 1940 (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: Home for the Aged of New York State (New York, NY), 1961- (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: Home for the Aged of New York State (New York, NY): Yearbook, 1978 (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: I.L. Peretz Schools (New York, NY), 1969- (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: I.L. Peretz Workmen's Circle School 2 (New York, NY), 1952 (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: I.L. Peretz Workmen's Circle School 5 (New York, NY), 1949- (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: Van Cortland Workmen's Circle Community House (New York, NY), 1970- (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Circle: Washington Heights Workmen's Circle School (New York, NY), undated (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Compensation Publicity Bureau (New York, NY), 1922 (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Educational Association, undated (Box 112)
  - Workmen's Mutual Fire Insurance Society (New York, NY), 1947- (Box 112)
  - Workshop for People's Art (New York, NY), 1976- (Box 112)
  - Workshop of Graphic Art (New York, NY), undated (Box 112)
  - World Affairs Center, 1959 (Box 112)
  - World Alliance for International Friendship Through the Churches, undated (Box 112)
  - World Anti-Communist League, China Chapter, Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, Republic of China I, 1974- (Box 112)
  - World Anti-Communist League, China Chapter, Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, Republic of China II, 1974- (Box 112)
  - World Assembly for Peace, 1969 (Box 112)
  - World Assembly of Youth, 1954-1956 (Box 130, Folder 23-25)
  - World Association for Adult Education, 1938 (Box 112)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Ottawa, Canada), 1971- (Box 112)
  - World Can't Wait, the, 2005-2007, undated (Box 112)
  - World Citizen's Forum (Belden, CA), 1945 (Box 112)
  - World Committee for a World Constitutional Convention (Denver, CO), 1963 (Box 112)
  - World Committee for the Victims of German Fascism, 1933 (Box 112)
  - World Community of Al-Islam in the West, 1963 (Box 112)
  - World Conference of Working Women (Budapest, Hungary), 1956 (Box 112)
  - World Congress for Peace, 1949 (Box 112)
  - World Congress of Peace Forces, 1975 (Box 112)
  - World Congress for Peace, National Independence and Disarmament (Helsinki, Finland), 1965 (Box 112)
  - World Council of Churches: Programme to Combat Racism, 1973- (Box 112)
  - World Council of Peace, 1952-1963 (Box 112)
  - World Council of Peace, 1965- (Box 112)
  - World Federalists Association (Arlington, VA), undated (Box 112)
  - World Federalists, USA, 1946- (Box 112)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth I, 1945- (Box 112)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth II, 1945- (Box 112)
  - World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship I, 1947- (Box 113)
  - World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship II, 1947-1984 (Box 113)
  - World Friendship Center (New Hampshire), 2010 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Association (Jenkins, MN), undated (Box 113)
  - World Peace Brigade, 1962- (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1970-1972 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1970-1972 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council III, 1970-1972 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council, 1973-1974 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1974 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1974 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1975 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1975 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council III, 1975 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1976-1977 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1976-1977 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1978 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1978 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council III, 1978 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council, 1979-1981 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1982-1983 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1982-1983 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council I, 1984-1989 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council II, 1984-1989 (Box 113)
  - World Peace Council III, 1984-1989 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Council, 1994 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Council, undated (Box 114)
  - World Peace Council: Press Releases and Publicity, 1970- (Box 114)
  - World Peace Fellowship, 1921 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Foundation, 1934- (Box 114)
  - World Peace Foundation: Pamphlets I, 1935-1936 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Foundation: Pamphlets II, 1935-1936 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Society, 1968 (Box 114)
  - World Peace Study Mission, 1965- (Box 114)
  - World Peace Tax Fund, 1984 (Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 14)
  - World Socialist Party of the United States (Boston, MA), 1974- (Box 114)
  - World Socialist Web Site, 2001-2005, undated (Box 114)
  - World Student Congress, 1953- (Box 114)
  - World Veterans Foundation, 1963- (Box 114)
  - World View Publishers I, 1970- (Box 114)
  - World View Publishers II, 1970- (Box 114)
  - World View Publishers III, 1970- (Box 114)
  - World View Publishers IV, 1970- (Box 114)
  - World Without War Council (Berkeley, CA), 1947- (Box 114)
  - World Youth Congress, 1938- (Box 114)
  - Wounded Knee Legal Defense/Offense Committee, 1973- (Box 114)
  - WPAX (Radio Station) (New York, NY), 1971- (Box 114)
  - Writers and Editors War Tax Protest, undated (Box 114)
  - Writers' War Board (New York, NY), 1945- (Box 114)
- X, 1958; 1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton
  - Xavier Institute of Industrial Relations (New York, NY), 1958- (Box 114)
- Y, 1922-2011; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 shared manuscript box, and 1 oversize shared box
  - Yale Socialist Union, 1964 (Box 114)
  - Yale University, 1970 (Box 114)
  - Ya-Ya Network (Youth Activists - Youth Allies), undated (Box 114)
  - Yes, Bush Can!, 2004 (Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 15)
  - Yiddish Art Theatre (New York, NY), 1928- (Box 114)
  - Yivo Institute for Jewish Research I, 1944- (Box 114)
  - Yivo Institute for Jewish Research II, 1944- (Box 114)
  - Yorkville German American Peace Committee, undated (Box 114)
  - Yorkville Neighborhood Association, undated (Box 114)
  - Young Adult Council/ National Social Welfare Assembly, 1953- (Box 114)
  - Young Americans for Freedom I, 1961- (Box 114)
  - Young Americans for Freedom II, 1961- (Box 114)
  - Young Atheist League (Seattle, WA), undated (Box 114)
  - Young Circle League of America, 1929- (Box 114)
  - Young Circle League of America I, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Circle League of America II, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Citizens Political Action Committee, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Communist International, 1922-1923 (Box 115)
  - Young Communist International, 1924-1929, undated (Box 121)
  - Young Communist International: Programme, 1923, undated (Box 121)
  - Young Communist League of Canada, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Democratic Socialists, 1999-, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Eclectic Liberation Leaders!, 2007- (Box 115)
  - Young Lords Organization, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Lords Party, 1969-1972 (Box 115, Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 16)
  - Young Lords Party, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Partisans (Richmond, CA), circa 1970s (Box 115)
  - Young People's Socialist League, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 17)
  - Young Pioneers of America, 1929 (Box 115)
  - Young Progressives of America, 1948- (Box 115)
  - Young Republicans of the University of California, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Social Democrats, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 18)
  - Young Socialist Alliance in Canada, 1961-1973 (Box 115, Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 19)
  - Young Socialist League, 1955-1958 (Box 115)
  - Young Socialists, 1972-1976, undated (Box 115)
  - Young Poale Zion of America, 1937- (Box 115)
  - Young Voters for Johnson (New York, NY), undated (Box 115)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA), undated (Box 115)
  - Young Workers Liberation League, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism, 1963-1968 (Box 115, Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 20)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism, 1969- (Box 115)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism: Women's Caucus, 1970, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Anti-Fascist Committee, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Bloc, undated (Box 115, Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 21)
  - Youth Committee Against Fascism (Chicago, IL), undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee Against Poverty, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee Against War I, 1938- (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee Against War II, 1938- (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee Against War III, 1938- (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee for Democracy, 1942 (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee for Peace and Democracy in the Middle East, 1971 (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee for the Oxford Pledge, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Committee on Peace, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Empowered Action, 2011 (Box 115)
  - Youth Defense Campaign, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth for International Socialism, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth for New America, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth for Stalin, 1968 (Box 115)
  - Youth for Victory Council, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth in Action, 1977 (Box 115)
  - Youth in Focus, 1940 (Box 115)
  - Youth Institute for Peace and Democracy in the Middle East (New York, NY), 1971- (Box 115)
  - Youth International Party, 1968-1982 (Box 115, Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 22, Box Shared Tamiment 187, Folder 12)
  - Youth Leadership Support Network, 2002, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Liberation I, 1971- (Box 115)
  - Youth Liberation II, 1971- (Box 115)
  - Youth Liberation Press, 1975- (Box 115)
  - Youth March for Integrated Schools, circa 1959 (Box 115)
  - Youth Peace/War Resisters League (New York, NY), undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Publications (New York, NY), 1960-, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Publishers (New York, NY), 1932-1935 (Box 115)
  - Youth Revival for Survival (New York, NY), 1986 (Box 115)
  - Youth United for Jobs, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Vote Coalition, 2003, undated (Box 115)
  - Youth Zionist Organization of America, 1935 (Box 115)
- Z, 1931-2005; 1 linear foot in 1 record carton
  - Z Magazine (Boston, MA), 1988 (Box 115)
  - Zendik, 2005- (Box 115)
  - Zentralantiquariat Der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik, 1974 (Box 115)
  - Zerowork, 1976 (Box 115)
  - Zhongguo Guo Ji Shu Dian (Peking, China), 1962 (Box 115)
  - Zimbabwe African National Union, 1976- (Box 115)
  - Zinn Education Project, undated (Box 115)
  - Zionist Socialist Party (Tsiyonistish-Sotsyalistishe Arbeyter Partey) (Soviet Union), 1931 (Box 115)
  - Zippies, 1972 (Box 115)